GAN SAU YANG

BLK495A, Tampines street 43, 520495

Mobile No: +6587561236 WhatsApp: +60162786399

Portfolio: https://github.com/sauyang/portfolio.git

Sauyang1009@gmail.com

Expected Salary: SGD 4200



Objective

I am currently looking for a new opportunity. Interested on IT-related job that I can work to improve myself and my skills, so that it allows me becoming better at what I do. 3 years mobile android developer working experience.

Relevant job skills: capable of android native mobile app and basic IOS. Interested on creating mobile app, drawing its layout UI/UX and challenging.

Tedious task because there are many OS versions, make sure app is bug free and optimum performance for many different android OS.

Skills

- Android SDK
- Version Control System using Subversion, Git Bitbucket
- Kotlin & Java programming
- Webservice REST, SOAP XML & JSON format
- Google Play Service, Map, Firebase FCM, Notification and Crashlytics
- Android App pen-test using Jenkins
- Microsoft Azure hosting Web-app (ASP.NET)

Education

ASIA PACIFIC UNIVERSITY - Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science/Information Technology

May 2011 - Dec 2015

- Experience on configuring, monitoring, upgrading and maintaining systems hardware, software and related infrastructure.
- Networking knowledge (Mobile & Wireless Technology) such as DHCP, routing, switching and VOIP.
- Android Java programming knowledge, Programming C & C++, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Office, Cloud hosting Web-App using Microsoft Azure and Microsoft ASP.Net.

Working Experience

Mobile Android developer - Silverlake Mobility Ecosystem SDN BHD

May 2016 – Jan 2019

- Develop digital banking modules for consumer bank Hong Leong Connect (Malaysia) & Hong Leong Connect Vietnam such as Online transfer, Account Overview, Credit Card Service and so on.
- UI/UX design using Android Native layout, ensure layout & code are easily readable and maintable by using XML, component or MVC pattern.
- Integrating web-services request & response from server-side and got the experience of using HttpsURLConnection for rest service call, SOAP XML and JSON format.
- Technical skills, Android Native SDK knowledge such as permission, camera and Android OS behavior. Google Play services, Firebase Crashlytics, Google Map (GPS enabled) view nearby bank branches, location is determined by GPS signals. Solving Android OS compatibility issues, such as replacing deprecated SDK calling methods.

Mobile Android developer - Pactera Singapore PTE LTD

FEB 2019 – April 2020

- Project: DBS IDEAL mobile banking app for business. Developing business transaction modules such as fund transfer module, scan & pay integration using third-

party QR and Google FCM notification for Manage Alerts modules.

- Payee Creation & Management, supporting overseas fund transfer to many foreign

banks. User can easily select the created payee to proceed the type of fund transfer.

Message from DBS module, allow user to choose image, PDF and various extension

file with text message, send it as a message for inquiry, report an issue or feedback.

Manage Alerts module, allowing user to check transaction alert such as high/low

balance it will remind user when the account balance is reaching the high/low balance,

there are many types of alerts user can choose to activate.

- Third party integration, V-KEY software token for DBS IDEAL Digital token.

Ensures digital token 2FA is working for mobile devices (needed for transaction

requests), replacing traditional hardware token OTP & SMS OTP.

- Adding Android fingerprint feature for quick login and transaction approval, extra

encryption with cipher and SecretKey store in AndroidKeystore to avoid fingerprint

bypass.

Hobby

Running, Hiking, Workout & Yoga.

*I am not convenient to pick up a call during working hours, please contact me via

WhatsApp : +60162786399 or Email : <u>sauyang1009@gmail.com</u>

I will reply as soon as possible, thanks alot.

3 •